so something some people say that we
only live once [Music]
well youth if you are an authentic
person I mean many people say that as a
form of dismissal ah
you only live once there's nothing you
can say to them but say people start
doubting that notion of you only live
once the fact is you don't really know
how many times you live so as simple as
that you can't know
you cannot know there are people who
believe they live only once the people
who believe do you live many times
they're people who believe you live
twice such as rebirth in heaven or hell
and that's it but the point is it's
always going to remain a matter of
belief so if you're somebody who is
trying to help yourself in an ultimate
manner you want to develop your mind and
so you would write you have you have to
recognize that and admit that it's
always gonna be a matter of belief so
when you are sure when you feel
completely confident saying you live
only once well that's not true because
you don't know for sure yet you being
sure based upon a mere belief it's a
it's a it's an it's a it's a big mistake
it's a very risky thing to do so I'm not
saying you should stop believing
whatever you believe I'm just saying you
have to recognize it that it is a belief
and it cannot be more than that so from
that point of view then you recognize
well what is the safest belief
can have like if I live only once if I
believe that okay
sure and then as a result of that belief
I end up behaving in this life whichever
way I want but what if what if you live
more than once and then because of your
bad behavior in this life you end up
paying the price because those people
who do believe in future lives be
Christian or Buddhist or Hindus they
believe that you're going to be reborn
accordingly to your actions even
Christians like if you if you are not a
good Christian having heavens those will
be close to you so you recognize it so
okay so the belief of more lives
requires a certain degree of good
behavior in the sense of if you don't
behave well your future lives it's going
to be they're gonna be very compromised
so that's all you have to do you don't
have to go further now you have to look
for a proof you just require to
recognize it it's a belief and as such
the best belief for you to adopt is the
one that safest in the long run as with
everything else in the life you don't
have thing just for tomorrow oh I'll
just steal this today enjoy the money no
enjoy enjoy the money I stole tomorrow
and then they have tomorrow gonna go to
jail for the rest of my life that's a
very unwise thing to do so in the same
manner you recognize there might be only
one life there might be more lives but I
should assume that there more lives in
case that there are more lives and then
I end up paying the price for my
misbehavior in this life and that's it
and it's not exactly that you need to
relinquish this life in order to gain
heaven in future lives you just have to
not behave like an animal in this life
that's it you just have to be have a
degree of virtue that's what everybody
agrees about so what is the safest
safest route for you to go it's
basically to believe that there probably
more lives just in case if they're not
so big you behave well in this life
people praise you people you were
trustworthy they trusted you you never
let down by you you were not you're not
a scoundrel not stealing and whatever
cheating so you behave properly and you were
so you behave properly and you were
rewarded right away with respect
and people wanted to help you and then
if there were if there if there are
future lives you're gonna be rewarded
even more according to those who believe
in that if not we'll submit and this
whole thing like oh I need to people
should do whatever makes them happy
probably about 3/4 of people don't
really know what makes them happy which
means for them happiness is the
experience when when they're not
experiencing unhappiness which means for
them pursuit of happiness is actively
running away from the prospect of
unhappiness which means your whole life
revolves around running away from
experiencing unpleasant feelings that's
your definition of happiness being being
on a constant being constantly chased by
unhappiness and anxiety exactly exactly
and that's what that's what that's what
definition of happiness becomes for
people and it's if you look at it that's
exactly how people live their lives
that's why there's so many like issues
in the modern society like with people
with men like mental problems developing
them too much in so much pressure too
much stress they can't deal with it
medications everything else vices giving
into to extreme measures because you
don't know what to do anymore
you're proliferated in that escape so
much and took it and it's face value
what took it as as if it's sort of a
good thing now you just do whatever
makes you happy what makes me happy
well I'm happy when I don't experience
unhappiness so then what my smooth I
must prevent unhappiness at all cost and
then you become very stressed and then
sensuality becomes the only mean of of
gaining some degree of happiness but
it's not happiness there's just
management of your
which of course from the point of view
of that unhappiness is happiness but
it's a very relative happiness it's not
really a happiness that they can last
well the happiness that lies the
happiness in itself which means it's its
happiness of freedom happiness of being
above things that can affect you not be
not kind of happiness of necessity like
I need to keep running away because it's
this beast chasing me that's not
happiness you might feel a relief when
you feel like oh you're temporarily safe
from the beast and there is happiness
from the obviously the threat the
imminent threat of the beast attacking
you but overall you're still not free
from the beast which means that's only a
relative happiness and that beast is
basically any form of suffering in this
life internal external any anxiety fear
stress burden loss any any of that it's
basically an example of the beast you're
running away from because the mind is
just edits face value what it does when
it experienced suffering it turns away
from it wants to get rid of it wants to
prevent it and that becomes a definition
of the of the purpose of your life just
running and that's what people
compulsively give into the sensual
desire it's not optional there is no
matter I can I will refrain from
sensuality today unless the circumstance
is refraining that's why that's why it's
not it's not it's almost mandatory for
people to why because they chose the
path of running away would you equals to
say they chose the path of just taking
their desires at the face value which
means they won't be able to resist them
that's why you're bound you're bound by
the desire you're bound by fear you're
bound by running away from from from
suffering so any happen is the chicken
experience be within that which means it's amazing
be within that which means it's amazing
happiness